ALUN CENNYTH STOKES

McMaster University, Hamilton, ON stokea1@mcmaster.ca +1 (647)-287-2418

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My interests lie in computing and mathematics, particularly number theory and symbolic algebra. I am currently interested in dessins d'enfants and the computation of their Belyi maps. I write software for high-performance and distributed computing and have substantial experience in various machine learning techniques.

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Pure Mathematics)

September 2021 - April 2023

McMaster University

Supervisor: Dr Cameron Franc

Bachelor of Integrated Science (Mathematics & Statistics) September 2017 - June 2021

McMaster University Honours: summa cum laude (10.8/12 GPA) Supervisor: Dr Cameron Franc The Search for Self-Contained Numbers

Turner Fenton Secondary School

September 2013 - June 2017 International Baccalaureate Program 97% Cumulative Average

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Stokes, A. Hum, W., Zaslavsky, J. STEM Fellowship Journal. 6(1): 1-5. Available at A Minimal-Input Multilayer Perceptron for Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions.
- [2] *Stokes, A. Automatically Solving Square-Piece Jigsaw Puzzles using Convolutional Neural Networks with Gradient Boosted Decision Trees. The Undergraduate Journal. (12th edition). Accessible at: Automatically Solving Square-Piece Jigsaw Puzzles.
- A. The search for self-contained numbers: [3] †Stokes, k-special 3-smooth representations and the Collatz conjecture. MacSphere, 2021, [Online]. Available at: The search for self-contained numbers.

Entries marked with † have **not** been peer-reviewed.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

May 2021 - August 2021 Dr Cameron Franc

McMaster University

Investigated machine learning strategies to discriminate non-congruence finite-index subgroups of the modular group and compute Belyi maps corresponding to dessins d'enfants.

Data Scientist

June 2020 - August 2020

Statistics Canada

Consumer Prices Division

Developed NLP methods for hierarchical data structure mapping to aid in calculating the consumer price index.

Research Assistant

May 2020 - July 2020

McMaster University

Dr George Dragomir, Dr Andy Nicas

Building on work by Dragomir and Nicas, we investigated how quasi-hyperbolicity could be exploited to reduce roughness and distortion in quasi-isometric graph embeddings.

Research Assistant

May 2019 - May 2020

McMaster University

Dr Ned Nedialkov

Developed convolutional neural networks to segment photoacoustic breast images for a group from Western University developing a hand-held in-situ scanner.

TALKS AND SEMINARS

[†]Algebra and Algebraic Geometry Seminar

November 2021

McMaster University

An Introduction to Belyi Maps

Gave a 30-minute presentation on dessins d'enfants, their relevance, and pertinent computational techniques used in my research open to McMaster's math faculty and graduate students.

Synopsis 2021 April 2021

McMaster University

k-special 3-smooth Representations and the Collatz Conjecture

A 15-minute expository talk on a formulation of the Collatz conjecture by a family of Diophantine equations and a conjecturally sparse set of numbers that are 'almost' solutions.

CANDEV January 2020

Government of Canada Using Transformer-based Embeddings to Identify Course Redundancies

Gave a short talk on our use of transfer-learning with a transformer model to cluster courses offered by the Canadian School of Public Service and identify redundancies in course offerings.

[†]Undergraduate Big Data Competition

July 2019

STEM Fellowship

Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions Without Knowledge of Drug Structure

This was a talk given with coauthors on our method of using machine learning to predict *in-vivo* drug-drug interactions using only analytical chemical properties. This was held at York University.

Synopsis 2019 April 2019

McMaster University

Prime Distribution by Linear Flow on the Torus

A 15 minute expository talk on the primary findings of a 4-month project investigating prime distributions over non-intersecting curves on closed surfaces.

Entries marked with † are invited talks.

GRANTS AND AWARDS

Ontario Graduate Scholarship

May 2022 - April 2023

\$15000

Competitive

NSERC USRA

May 2021 - August 2021

\$8120

Competitive

Dean's Honour List

September 2017 - April 2021

Awarded all 4 years of undergraduate degree

Non-competitive

Global Undergraduate Awards

September 2020

1st place for computer science in North America

Competitive

McMaster Stewart Award

May 2020

\$3750

Competitive

CANDEV Data Challenge

January 2020 Competitive

 1^{st} place

STEM Fellowship Big Data Competition

July 2019

\$3000

Competitive

McMaster President's Award

September 2017

\$2500 Non-competitive

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS

McMaster University

January 2022 - April 2022

Graduate Topics in Risk Management

MFM 763 MATH 3H03

 $Introductory\ Number\ Theory$

September 2021 - December 2021

McMaster University
Numerical Linear Algebra

MATH 3NA3

Linear Algebra I

MATH 1B03

McMaster University

January 2021 - April 2021

Introduction to Discrete Mathematics

 $\stackrel{\circ}{CS}$ 1DM3

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages[†] Python, Julia, Java, MATLAB, C/C++, CUDA, JavaScript,

SQL, PHP, Mathematica

Major Libraries[†]

SageMath, Pytorch, HomotopyContinuation.jl, Macuaulay2

Software & Tools

LATEX, Git, MySQL

Operating Systems[†]

GNU/Linux (Ubuntu, primarily), MacOS, Windows

Bolding indicates preferntiality

OTHER PROJECTS

Global Undergraduate Awards

September 2021

Dr Ned Nedialkov

Fully Automated Jigsaw Puzzle Solving by Hybrid ML

Won first place in North America for a paper on hybrid machine learning techniques to solve squarepiece jigsaws; state-of-the-art matching accuracy was reported.

National Big Data Competition

June 2020

Dr Yasaman Amannejad

Medication Recommendation by Matrix Factorization

Devised a matrix factorization-based recommender system to predict effective drugs for treating several mental illnesses, given a patient's history with other drugs.

REFERENCES

Are available upon request, preferably made to stokeal@mcmaster.ca.

 $^{^{\}dagger} \mathrm{Listed}$ in order of proficiency